<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><sp:scientific_paper xmlns:sp="https://github.com/nikolina97/xws-tim16-siit-2019" xmlns:pred="https://schema.org/" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" about="http://ftn.uns.ac.rs/paper/paper3" id="paper3" typeof="pred:ScholarlyArticle">
	<sp:title datatype="xs:string" property="pred:headline">End to End Neural OMR</sp:title>
	<sp:authors>
		<sp:author href="http://ftn.uns.ac.rs/person/milos.radojcin@uns.ac.rs" rel="pred:author" typeof="pred:Person">
			<sp:first_name about="http://ftn.uns.ac.rs/person/milos.radojcin@uns.ac.rs" datatype="xs:string" property="pred:first_name">Milos</sp:first_name>
			<sp:last_name about="http://ftn.uns.ac.rs/person/milos.radojcin@uns.ac.rs" datatype="xs:string" property="pred:last_name">Radojcin</sp:last_name>
			<sp:university>
				<sp:name>University of Novi Sad</sp:name>
				<sp:city>Novi Sad</sp:city>
				<sp:country>Serbia</sp:country>
			</sp:university>
			<sp:email>milos.radojcin@uns.ac.rs</sp:email>
		</sp:author>
		<sp:author href="http://ftn.uns.ac.rs/person/nikolina.batinic@uns.ac.rs" rel="pred:author" typeof="pred:Person">
			<sp:first_name about="http://ftn.uns.ac.rs/person/nikolina.batinic@uns.ac.rs" datatype="xs:string" property="pred:first_name">Nikolina</sp:first_name>
			<sp:last_name about="http://ftn.uns.ac.rs/person/nikolina.batinic@uns.ac.rs" datatype="xs:string" property="pred:last_name">Batinic</sp:last_name>
			<sp:university>
				<sp:name>University of Novi Sad</sp:name>
				<sp:city>Novi Sad</sp:city>
				<sp:country>Serbia</sp:country>
			</sp:university>
			<sp:email>nikolina.batinic@uns.ac.rs</sp:email>
		</sp:author>
	</sp:authors>
	<sp:abstract id="paper3/abstract">
		<sp:paragraph id="paper3/abstract/paragraph1">
			Up till now, the development of mining industry in China has followed the road of the overseas introduction and absorption, independent innovation and technology export.
			Mere English reading ability can hardly meet the demands of high-level professionals to export research achievements.
			To improve the graduate students’ ability to write English scientific papers on mining industry has become one of the main tasks to cultivate mining engineering professionals.
			Considering the current condition of China’s test-oriented education, the mode to efficiently and quickly enhance graduate students’ English writing ability of scientific papers
			on mining industry has been proposed, specifically, intensively reading high-level English scientific papers on mining industry, writing the Chinese version
			according to the requirements of the corresponding English scientific paper, rewriting the paper in English based on the Chinese version,
			performing language refinement and polish by experts or institutions, finally completing the paper through communication and exchange with the experts.
		</sp:paragraph>
		<sp:keywords>
			<sp:keyword datatype="xs:string" property="pred:keyword">mining engineering</sp:keyword>
			<sp:keyword datatype="xs:string" property="pred:keyword">scientific paper</sp:keyword>
		</sp:keywords>
	</sp:abstract>
	<sp:chapters>
		<sp:chapter id="paper3/chapter1">
			<sp:subtitle>Introduction</sp:subtitle>
			<sp:paragraph id="paper3/chapter1/paragraph1">
				Mining industry is to be a fundamental one of the national economy construction.
				Since its founding, China has witnessed three stages of mining industry development: the beginning stage of overseas introduction and absorption,
				the stage of independent self-development and the disseminating stage of exporting technology, which have provided the crucial support of mineral resources
				for the national economy and promoted the economic and social development of China.
			</sp:paragraph>
			<sp:subchapter id="paper3/chapter1/subchapter1">
				<sp:subtitle>The Instructional Model to Improve Graduate Students’ Ability to Read English Scientific Papers</sp:subtitle>
				<sp:paragraph id="paper3/chapter1/subchapter1/paragraph1">
					To improve postgraduates’ English comprehension through intensively reading the high-standard English scientific papers on mining industry. [1]
				</sp:paragraph>
				<sp:paragraph id="paper3/chapter1/subchapter1/paragraph2">
					The introduction part of an English scientific paper, a succinct generalization of the current situation and trend in the relevant research field,
					is vital to the entire writing process, calling for plenty of literature reading. Literature reading on the one hand enables graduates to know and keep track
					of the research trend, research subject and research level related to the paper to be written, so as to ensure the innovation, quality and significance of the paper.
					On the other hand, it can enhance reading comprehension of scientific papers written in English.
					The good understanding of English scientific papers lays the foundation for writing such papers in an easy-to-understand way. [0]
				</sp:paragraph>
			</sp:subchapter>
		</sp:chapter>
	</sp:chapters>
	<sp:references>
        <sp:reference href="http://ftn.uns.ac.rs/paper/paper1" id="paper3/reference1" rel="pred:reference">
            <sp:ref_number>[0]</sp:ref_number>
            <sp:ref_author>Katarina Aleksic</sp:ref_author>
            <sp:article_name>Applications of RISM data</sp:article_name>
            <sp:year>2020</sp:year>
        </sp:reference>
		<sp:reference href="http://ftn.uns.ac.rs/paper/paper2" id="paper3/reference2" rel="pred:reference">
            <sp:ref_number>[1]</sp:ref_number>
            <sp:ref_author>Nikolina Batinic</sp:ref_author>
            <sp:article_name>End to End Neural OMR</sp:article_name>
            <sp:year>2020</sp:year>
        </sp:reference>
    </sp:references>
	<sp:category datatype="xs:string" property="pred:category">original research</sp:category>
<sp:version datatype="xs:string" property="pred:version">1</sp:version>
    <sp:dateReceived datatype="xs:string" property="pred:dateReceived">2020-06-20</sp:dateReceived>
    <sp:state datatype="xs:string" property="pred:state">accepted</sp:state>
</sp:scientific_paper>